<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Do older players get evicted earlier in BigBrotherUS?</title>
      <link>/2023/08/31/do-older-players-get-evicted-earlier-in-bigbrotherus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2023/08/31/do-older-players-get-evicted-earlier-in-bigbrotherus/</guid>
      <description>Visualize the spread of player ages across all seasons as a histogramFigure 1: Data plotted as the number of houseguets (y-axis) that fall in to each category. Each bar representes 2 years of age. The mean and median player ages are indicated by couloured vertical dashed lines.Key Insights:Visual inspection of the distribution of players indicates that most BBUS houseguests are in their mid-late 20’s during the filming of their seasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How long does the surviving week 1 nominee last in the game?</title>
      <link>/2023/08/28/how-long-does-the-surviving-week-1-nominee-last-in-the-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2023/08/28/how-long-does-the-surviving-week-1-nominee-last-in-the-game/</guid>
      <description>Each season, at least one player survives the block in the first week.
We wondered how does being a surviving week 1 nominee affect game outcomes?Step 1: Graph how far each surviving first week nominee made in on their season of BBUS:Figure 1: Data plotted as each seasons first nominee (y-axis) with that players place on their season represented on the x-axis. Peach points(left) represent the starting humber of players on each season.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OTEV Analysis</title>
      <link>/2023/08/28/otev-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2023/08/28/otev-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Make Graph of which week OTEV was played in each season:Figure 1: Seasons of BBUS where OTEV was played (y-axis) plotted against which week in the season OTEV appeared (y-axis).Key Insights:Since it was first introduced during season 7, OTEV has been played every season except for season 10.Each season OTEV has appearead as a different wacky character, but the fundamentals of the game have remained consistent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is winning the first or second HOH competition advantageous in BBUS?</title>
      <link>/2023/08/27/is-winning-the-first-or-second-hoh-competition-advantageous-in-bbus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2023/08/27/is-winning-the-first-or-second-hoh-competition-advantageous-in-bbus/</guid>
      <description>Question: Is winning the first HOH good or bad for players’ games?Players often mention that they don’t want to win the first HOH, as not to “put a target on their back”.Is there systematic evidence to support an effect of winning the first HOH on game outcomes? (Explored below)Graph where each first HOH placed on thir season of BBUS:Figure 1: Each week 1 HOH’s final place on their season of BBUs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
